Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to another podcast here with us at EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一期播客。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you another part of our sports series and this time it's an
今天我们要带来体育系列的又一部分，这次是
advanced lesson.
高级课程。
That's right.
没错。
We're heading to the mountains today to take a skiing lesson.
今天我们要去山上上一堂滑雪课。
Alright, so we're going to be learning about skiing, a winter sport and very popular throughout
好的，所以我们要学习滑雪，这是一项冬季运动，在全世界
the world.
都很受欢迎。
But before we get started, why don't we take a look at a couple of words in Vocabulary
但在开始之前，我们先来看看词汇预览中的几个词。
Preview.
词汇预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
Alright, so we're going to hear these two words in our dialogue.
好的，我们会在对话中听到这两个词。
The first one is fresh powder.
第一个是“fresh powder”。
Fresh powder.
“Fresh powder”。
Okay, so powder.
好的，所以“powder”。
We probably know this phrase already.
我们可能已经知道这个短语了。
Yeah, but here we're talking about fresh light snow.
是的，但这里我们说的是新鲜的轻雪。
So fresh light snow, snow that recently fell.
所以是新鲜的轻雪，刚下的雪。
Yep.
对。
Okay, so it looks like powder.
好的，它看起来像粉末。
The best kind for skiing on.
最适合滑雪的那种。
Okay, the best kind.
好的，最好的那种。
Alright, so fresh powder.
好的，所以是“fresh powder”。
What about our next phrase?
那下一个短语呢？
Well, we're also going to meet a four-time giant slalom champion.
嗯，我们还会遇到一位四次大回转冠军。
Alright, a four-time giant slalom champion.
好的，一位四次大回转冠军。
Okay, so giant slalom is a type of ski race.
好的，所以“giant slalom”是一种滑雪比赛。
When you probably see it on TV when they go down the hill and they have to go through
你可能在电视上看到过，他们下山时必须穿过
these red or blue flags, right?
这些红色或蓝色的旗门，对吧？
Yep.
对。
Now, four-time giant slalom champion means he won the giant slalom four times.
现在，“four-time giant slalom champion”意味着他赢了四次大回转比赛。
Okay.
好的。
That's an interesting way of saying that somebody did something many times.
这是一种有趣的说法，表示某人多次做了某事。
Right.
对。
So I can say the three-time Nobel Prize winner.
所以可以说“three-time Nobel Prize winner”。
Yes, exactly.
是的，没错。
Okay.
好的。
Or the five-time Olympic gold medalist.
或者“five-time Olympic gold medalist”。
Okay, perfect.
好的，完美。
So now it's time for us to go to the mountains with our famous Rick Fields and Bob Copeland
所以现在是时候和我们著名的Rick Fields和Bob Copeland一起去山上了，
and we'll see what happens.
看看会发生什么。
Welcome, ski lovers of all ages.
欢迎，所有年龄段的滑雪爱好者。
My name is Rick Fields and here with me is the man that needs no introduction, Bob Copeland.
我是Rick Fields，和我一起的是无需介绍的人，Bob Copeland。
Thank you, Rick.
谢谢，Rick。
What a beautiful day here in Aspen, Colorado, where the sun is shining and we've got 12
在科罗拉多州阿斯彭，今天真是美好的一天，阳光明媚，我们有12
inches of fresh powder.
英寸的新鲜粉雪。
It doesn't get much better than this.
没有比这更好的了。
That's right, Bob.
没错，Bob。
But today we have a special treat for our viewers.
但今天我们的观众有一个特别的惊喜。
We're joined here by Ian Russe, four-time giant slalom champion.
我们请到了Ian Russe，四次大回转冠军。
And on this special edition of the show, Ian is going to teach us the basics of skiing.
在本期特别节目中，Ian将教我们滑雪的基础知识。
So let's hit the slopes.
所以让我们去滑雪吧。
Well, first off, let's get those boots on.
嗯，首先，让我们穿上靴子。
You're going to want to make sure your boots fit snugly.
你要确保你的靴子合脚。
That's right.
没错。
Now snap them into your bindings.
现在把它们卡进固定器里。
And you're also going to want a good pair of goggles to protect your eyes.
你还需要一副好的护目镜来保护眼睛。
It's a bright day today, so there's going to be a lot of glare out there on the slopes.
今天天气晴朗，所以雪道上会有很多眩光。
We don't want you hitting any of those moguls.
我们可不想让你撞上那些雪包。
Bob, since you're a beginner skier and might take a few spills, it's a good idea to have
Bob，既然你是初学者，可能会摔几跤，最好有
a good warm pair of dry ski gloves.
一副温暖干燥的滑雪手套。
Easy there, Rick.
别急，Rick。
Well, let's head over onto the chairlift and test your skills.
嗯，我们坐缆车上去，测试一下你的技巧。
All right, we're up here on the bunny hill.
好的，我们在初学者坡道上。
So Bob, why don't you do a few snowplow turns?
所以Bob，你来做几个犁式转弯吧。
Gnarly run, Rick.
很棒的滑道，Rick。
Nice carving.
漂亮的转弯。
You've got some mad skills.
你技术真棒。
That was sick.
太酷了。
You want to see gnarly?
你想看酷的吗？
Well, see that bump over there?
嗯，看到那边的雪包了吗？
I'm going to catch some major air.
我要飞起来了。
Butt plant.
屁股着地。
Ha ha ha.
哈哈哈。
He lost his skis.
他的滑雪板掉了。
Yard sale.
大甩卖。
Well, thanks for joining us here today.
嗯，感谢你今天加入我们。
I think that about does it.
我想差不多就这些了。
Bob, Ian, time for some après-ski?
Bob，Ian，该去滑雪后活动了吗？
No way, man.
不行，老兄。
We're off to grab some freshies.
我们要去滑新雪。
Pretty embarrassing for Rick there, wasn't it?
Rick那里挺尴尬的，是吧？
Yeah, he was a little bit cocky and then he ended up falling.
是啊，他有点自大，结果摔倒了。
Well, I think there's a lesson in that for all of us, but what the real lesson is today
嗯，我想这对我们所有人都是一个教训，但今天真正的教训
is language.
是语言。
So why don't we start with language takeaway?
所以我们为什么不从语言要点开始呢？
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, on language takeaway today, let's take a look at the first word.
好的，在今天的语言要点中，我们来看看第一个词。
We have some bindings.
我们有“bindings”。
Bindings.
“Bindings”。
Bindings are sort of like a lock that attaches your boot to your ski.
“Bindings”有点像一种锁，把你的靴子固定在滑雪板上。
So those are the bindings.
所以那就是固定器。
I guess it comes from the verb to bind.
我想它来自动词“to bind”。
Yeah, to tie something so that it stays.
是的，绑住某物让它固定。
Okay.
好的。
Binding.
“Binding”。
So for example, my bindings are broken.
所以例如，我的固定器坏了。
Okay.
好的。
And another piece of skiing equipment and very important is goggles.
另一件滑雪装备，非常重要，是“goggles”。
Goggles.
“Goggles”。
Okay, we have goggles now.
好的，我们现在有护目镜。
Yep.
对。
Not to be confused with Google.
不要和Google混淆。
It's spelled almost the same way, huh?
拼写几乎一样，是吧？
Yep.
对。
But goggles are kind of like, imagine a big pair of glasses that you wear when you ski.
但护目镜有点像，想象一副大眼镜，你滑雪时戴。
So it makes people kind of look like flies.
所以它让人看起来有点像苍蝇。
Yes.
是的。
They have these huge glasses.
他们有这种大眼镜。
Yeah.
对。
And you'll also see safety goggles, which you might wear if you are a mechanic fixing
你也会看到安全护目镜，你可能在修车时戴，
a car or someone working with wood or chemicals or what have you.
或者做木工、化学工作等。
Okay, so goggles basically protect your eyes from snow, from the sun, from anything.
好的，所以护目镜基本上保护你的眼睛免受雪、阳光和任何东西的伤害。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So moving on to our next ski word.
所以继续下一个滑雪词。
They said you should wear the goggles so that you don't accidentally go over the moguls.
他们说你应该戴护目镜，这样就不会意外撞上雪包。
Okay, moguls.
好的，“moguls”。
It sounds kind of strange.
听起来有点奇怪。
What are these things?
这是什么？
Basically these are the bumps that are in a ski hill.
基本上就是滑雪坡上的那些凸起。
Bumps.
凸起。
Okay, so they're kind of like mini little hills.
好的，所以它们有点像迷你小山。
Yep.
对。
And they're very difficult to ski over, right?
而且很难滑过去，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
You got to be pretty good to handle those moguls.
你得技术很好才能应付那些雪包。
Okay.
好的。
Now, since these guys are beginner skiers, they're starting out on the bunny hill.
现在，因为这些人都是初学者，他们从初学者坡道开始。
A bunny hill.
“Bunny hill”。
The bunny hill.
Okay.
好的。
Very popular among skiers.
在滑雪者中很受欢迎。
The bunny hill is the easiest hill.
“Bunny hill”是最简单的坡道。
So it's where the beginners start to learn.
所以是初学者开始学习的地方。
Yeah, all the kids.
是的，所有孩子。
All the kids are on the bunny hill.
所有孩子都在初学者坡道上。
All right.
好的。
And our final words.
最后几个词。
Actually, we're going to look at two words here because they mean almost exactly the
实际上，我们要看两个词，因为它们的意思几乎完全
same thing.
相同。
We heard the ski instructor say gnarly.
我们听到滑雪教练说“gnarly”。
Gnarly run.
“Gnarly run”。
Yeah, gnarly.
是的，“gnarly”。
So an interesting word.
一个有趣的词。
It's spelled G-N-A-R-L-E-Y.
拼写是G-N-A-R-L-E-Y。
Okay, but you don't say gnarly.
好的，但你不说“gnarly”。
No.
不。
You say gnarly.
你说“gnarly”。
Okay.
好的。
And a related word, sick.
还有一个相关的词，“sick”。
Okay.
好的。
Now, sick means to be sick, right?
现在，“sick”意思是生病，对吧？
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
Not here.
这里不是。
Let's listen to some examples to help us understand.
让我们听一些例子来帮助理解。
Example one.
例子一。
Those were some sick dance moves.
那些舞步太酷了。
You are amazing.
你太棒了。
Example two.
例子二。
Jack and I went to the beach yesterday and surfed some really gnarly waves.
杰克和我昨天去了海滩，冲了一些很酷的浪。
Example three.
例子三。
Man, the concha last night was sick.
老兄，昨晚的音乐会太棒了。
I can't believe we got front row seats.
真不敢相信我们坐到了前排座位。
Okay.
好的。
So, basically, gnarly and sick, they mean that it's amazing, it was cool.
所以，基本上，“gnarly”和“sick”意思是它很棒，很酷。
It's awesome.
太棒了。
Awesome.
很棒。
Yeah.
对。
So, these two words are very, very informal.
所以，这两个词非常非常不正式。
It's slang.
是俚语。
Yeah.
对。
And actually, skier slang.
实际上，是滑雪者俚语。
Both of these words, I think, originated with skiers, snowboarders, skateboarders.
这两个词，我想，都起源于滑雪者、单板滑雪者、滑板者。
Gnarly dudes.
酷哥们。
So, okay.
所以，好的。
So, that's all the words we have for language takeaway, but we have some great phrases that
这就是语言要点的所有词，但我们还有一些很棒的短语
we want to take a look at before we listen to the dialogue again.
想在再次听对话之前看一下。
So, it's time now for Fluency Builder.
所以现在是流利度构建的时间了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right.
好的。
So, Rick said that it is time to...
所以，Rick说该...
So, Rick invited everyone to start skiing by saying, let's hit the slopes.
所以，Rick邀请大家开始滑雪，说“let's hit the slopes”。
Okay.
好的。
So, to hit the slopes.
所以，“to hit the slopes”。
To hit the slopes.
“To hit the slopes”。
Okay.
好的。
Now, we want to hit the slopes.
现在，我们想“hit the slopes”。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Let's go skiing.
我们去滑雪吧。
Let's go to the mountain.
我们去山上吧。
Yep.
对。
Now, we can change the noun slope for something else, right?
现在，我们可以把名词“slope”换成别的，对吧？
Yeah.
对。
You can change it for a lot of other different nouns.
你可以把它换成很多其他不同的名词。
And why don't we hear some examples of how you can do that?
我们为什么不听听一些例子，看看你怎么能做到这一点呢？
Example one.
例子一。
I really have to hit the books and study for my exam tomorrow.
我真的得埋头苦读，为明天的考试复习了。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm really tired.
我真的很累。
I think I'm going to hit the bed now.
我想我现在要去睡觉了。
Example three.
例子三。
Honey, can we hit the supermarket on our way home?
亲爱的，我们回家的路上能顺便去趟超市吗？
I need to buy some milk.
我需要买些牛奶。
Okay, great.
好的，太好了。
So, great examples and now we understand how we can use the hit the something.
所以，这些例子很棒，现在我们明白了怎么用“hit the something”这个短语。
All right.
好的。
What about our next phrase?
那我们的下一个短语呢？
Well, Rick warned Bob that he might take a few spills.
嗯，里克警告鲍勃，他可能会摔几跤。
Okay.
好的。
So, to take a spill.
所以，“to take a spill”。
To take a spill.
“To take a spill”。
Take a spill.
“Take a spill”。
Fall.
摔倒。
To fall.
Yep.
是的。
It means like a light fall or...
它指的是轻微的摔倒，或者……
Yeah, a pretty dramatic fall.
对，也可能是比较严重的摔倒。
Pretty dramatic.
相当严重。
So, you fell.
所以，你摔倒了。
Yeah.
嗯。
So, for example, instead of saying, that little girl was riding her bike and she fell, I can
所以，举个例子，与其说“那个小女孩在骑自行车，她摔倒了”，我可以
say, that little girl was riding her bike and she took a bad spill.
说“那个小女孩在骑自行车，她重重地摔了一跤”。
Yep.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
So, to take a spill.
所以，“to take a spill”。
You have to use the verb take though.
不过你必须用动词“take”。
Yes, exactly.
是的，没错。
You cannot just spill.
你不能只说“spill”。
Okay.
好的。
You have to take a spill.
你必须说“take a spill”。
All right.
好的。
What about our next phrase?
那我们的下一个短语呢？
Well, you might take a spill when you catch some major air.
嗯，当你腾空很高的时候，可能会摔一跤。
Okay.
好的。
To catch some major air.
腾空而起。
So, am I catching something?
所以，我在抓什么东西吗？
How am I catching air?
我怎么抓空气呢？
That's impossible.
那不可能。
Well, imagine if you're jumping and your skis are catching the air.
嗯，想象一下你在跳跃，你的滑雪板抓住了空气。
Ah, okay.
啊，好的。
So, I'm in the air for a very long time maybe?
所以，我可能在空中待了很长时间？
Yeah.
是的。
When you catch some air, basically, it's like you're flying for a couple of seconds.
当你腾空而起时，基本上就像飞了几秒钟。
So, you're flying for a couple of seconds.
所以，你飞了几秒钟。
You're very high up in the air.
你在空中很高。
Yep.
对。
Okay.
好的。
To catch some air.
腾空而起。
Yeah.
是的。
And you'll hear this phrase when you're, you know, not only when you're talking about skiing,
你会听到这个短语，不仅是在谈论滑雪的时候，
but also maybe if you're, you know, you're driving your car really fast and it sort of
也可能是在你开车开得很快，车子
jumps up in the air for a minute, well, not a minute, a second, that would be catching
短暂地跳起来的时候——不是一分钟，是一秒钟——那也算是
air as well.
腾空。
Okay.
好的。
So, to catch air.
所以，腾空。
All right.
好的。
So, they finished skiing.
所以，他们滑完了雪。
They were kind of tired and he said, well, let's call it a day.
他们有点累了，他说，好吧，今天就到这里吧。
To call it a day.
今天就到这里。
Let's call it a day.
Let's go home.
回家吧。
It's over.
结束了。
Let's finish.
结束吧。
Let's finish the day.
结束这一天吧。
Yep.
对。
Let's call it a day and go home.
今天就到这里，回家吧。
And not before we go to our next word, to grab some freshies.
在我们进入下一个词之前，去滑点新雪。
All right.
好的。
Grab us some freshies.
去滑点新雪。
Grab some freshies.
滑点新雪。
Okay.
好的。
Freshies.
新雪。
What are these freshies?
这些新雪是什么？
Remember we talked about fresh powder?
还记得我们聊过的粉雪吗？
It's that.
就是那个。
So, it's an informal way of saying fresh powder.
所以，这是粉雪的非正式说法。
Yeah.
对。
Fresh powdery light snow.
粉状轻盈的新雪。
Okay.
好的。
Freshies.
新雪。
Yep.
嗯。
So, the snow that nobody has skied on before.
就是没人滑过的雪。
Really good phrases and some amazing vocabulary.
真是好短语和一些很棒的词汇。
Let's listen to this dialogue one last time and then we'll come back and talk a little
让我们最后听一遍这段对话，然后回来再聊聊
bit more about this really fun sport.
这项非常有趣的运动。
Welcome ski lovers of all ages.
欢迎各年龄段的滑雪爱好者。
My name is Rick Fields and here with me is the man that needs no introduction, Bob Copeland.
我是里克·菲尔兹，和我一起的是无需介绍的男人，鲍勃·科普兰。
Thank you, Rick.
谢谢你，里克。
What a beautiful day here in Aspen, Colorado, where the sun is shining and we've got 12
今天在科罗拉多州阿斯彭，天气真美，阳光明媚，我们有12
inches of fresh powder.
英寸的粉雪。
It doesn't get much better than this.
没有比这更好的了。
That's right, Bob.
没错，鲍勃。
But today we have a special treat for our viewers.
但今天，我们为观众准备了一份特别的礼物。
We're joined here by Ian Russe, four-time Giant Slalom champion.
我们请来了伊恩·鲁斯，四次大回转冠军。
And on this special edition of the show, Ian is going to teach us the basics of skiing.
在本期特别节目中，伊恩将教我们滑雪的基础知识。
So, let's hit the slopes.
那么，让我们去滑雪吧。
Well, first off, let's get those boots on.
首先，把靴子穿上。
You're going to want to make sure your boots fit snugly.
你要确保靴子合脚。
That's right.
没错。
Now, snap them into your bindings.
现在，把它们卡进固定器里。
And you're also going to want a good pair of goggles to protect your eyes.
你还需要一副好护目镜来保护眼睛。
It's a bright day today, so there's going to be a lot of glare out there on the slopes.
今天天气晴朗，雪道上会有很多反光。
We don't want you hitting any of those moguls.
我们可不想你撞上那些雪包。
Bob, since you're a beginner skier and might take a few spills, it's a good idea to have
鲍勃，既然你是初学者，可能会摔几跤，最好有
a good warm pair of dry ski gloves.
一双暖和干燥的滑雪手套。
Easy there, Rick.
别急，里克。
Well, let's head over onto the chairlift and test your skills.
好吧，我们坐缆车上去，测试一下你的技巧。
All right, we're up here on the bunny hill, so Bob, why don't you do a few snowplow turns.
好了，我们在初学者坡道上，鲍勃，不如做几个犁式转弯。
Gnarly run, Rick.
刺激的滑道，里克。
Nice carving.
漂亮的转弯。
You've got some mad skills.
你技术真棒。
That was sick.
那太酷了。
You want to see gnarly?
你想看看什么叫惊险吗？
Well, see that bump over there?
嗯，看到那边那个坡了吗？
I'm going to catch some major air.
我要飞得老高了。
Butt plant.
屁股着地。
Ha ha ha, he lost his skis.
哈哈哈，他的滑雪板掉了。
Yard sale.
摔得满地装备。
Well, thanks for joining us here today.
好了，感谢你今天加入我们。
I think that about does it.
我觉得差不多就这些了。
Bob, Ian, time for some après-ski?
鲍勃，伊恩，该去滑雪后派对了吗？
No way, man.
才不呢，老兄。
We're off to grab some freshies.
我们要去滑新雪。
We heard the guys talk about après-ski, and actually this is one of my favorite parts
我们听到他们提到“滑雪后派对”，实际上这是我最喜欢的部分之一
of skiing.
滑雪的乐趣。
What is this?
这是什么？
It sounds French.
听起来像法语。
Yeah, it is.
是的，确实是。
I guess the Frenchness sort of gives it an air of specialness, right?
我觉得法语味儿给它增添了一种特别的感觉，对吧？
But après-ski is basically the party that you have after you're finished skiing.
但“滑雪后派对”基本上就是滑完雪后开的派对。
So usually you would have parties after skiing.
所以通常滑完雪后会有派对。
Right, so you finish your ski day, you've called it a day, you've glided down those
对，所以你结束了一天的滑雪，收工了，从那些
slopes and you head on over to the lodge, the little cabin, grab a beer or two or maybe
雪坡上滑下来，然后去滑雪小屋，那个小木屋，喝上一两杯啤酒或者
some hot alcoholic drink and kick back and relax with your friends.
一些热酒精饮料，和朋友们放松一下。
Wow, so it's popular for families to go to a ski resort and stay there for a couple of
哇，所以家庭去滑雪度假村住上几天很流行。
days.
几天。
So this is when you would do this with your friends or family.
这就是你和朋友或家人一起做的事。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
If it's with your friends, it's going to last until late into the night.
如果是和朋友一起，会一直持续到深夜。
All right, so it sounds fun.
好吧，听起来很有趣。
And next time maybe if you go skiing with your friends and you guys are speaking English
下次如果你和朋友去滑雪，而且你们现在说英语，
now, you can use all these great phrases and maybe surprise your friends if you tell them,
你可以用所有这些好短语，也许还能让朋友惊喜，如果你告诉他们，
let's go grab some freshies or something like that.
我们去滑点新雪之类的。
Yeah, you'll sound pretty, pretty dialed, pretty cool.
是啊，你会听起来很专业，很酷。
All right, so that's all the time we have for today.
好了，今天的时间就到这里。
Be sure to check out our website englishpod.com.
一定要访问我们的网站 englishpod.com。
Marco and I are always around to answer your questions and well, thanks for downloading.
马可和我随时都在，回答你的问题，嗯，感谢下载。
Until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
拜拜。